# ODUOR **SAMUEL**

Nairobi, Kenya 2159 +254790648600 Soduor15@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>website</u>

I am a software engineer with over 5 years of experience specializing in developing highly scalable and available distributed systems. With a passion for solving both simple and complex real-world challenges through technology, I am dedicated to integrating Agile methodologies into software delivery, always keeping the customer at the forefront of each release.

#### SKILLS

- JAVA (SPRING BOOT)
- NODE JS (EXPRESS JS, HAPPI JS)
- ANGULAR
- SQL (POSTGRESQL, SQL SERVER)
- NoSQL (MONGO DB)
- CASSANDRA
- DOCKER
- AWS
- KAFKA

- RABBITMQ
- REDIS
- ELK (ELASTICSEARCH, LOGSTASH, KIBANA)
- SPLUNK
- GIT
- SFTP
- SMPP
- TIBCO

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# JUNE 2021- CURRENT SYSTEM ENGINEER, SAFARICOM PLC

- Developed key features for the Hustler Fund personal loan product, contributing to 17M+
   registered customers, facilitating 48B+ in loan disbursements, and processing 57M+
   transactions within a year, ensuring 99.99% service availability, aiding the organization and
   Kenyan government in meeting their targets.
- Implemented Women Enterprise Fund and Hustler Groups, resulting in 1.5M+ registered groups and facilitating over 200M in loan disbursements, ensuring 99.99% service availability within one year of launch.
- Created the Faraja initiative, providing Safaricom customers with pre-approved, interest-free
  in-store credit for essential items, resulting in 714K+ active subscribers, over 106M
  disbursed with one merchant, and 99.99% service availability one-year post-launch.
- Collaborated with SME Credit Squad to develop the Boost La Biashara Query Service, supporting over 5,000 whitelisted TDRs in field marketing efforts for the Boost Ya Biashara product.

#### JUNE 2019- JUN 2021

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TECH FACTORY LIMITED**

• Revamped and built Mitkursus, a Danish white-label e-learning platform, leading to **50+ course providers** signing up across Denmark and Poland, with over **100 daily enrollments**.

#### **MAY 2018- AUGUST 2018**

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, AMPATH**

- Developed AMPATH Hotspot Monitoring Frontend to optimize network performance by efficiently monitoring bandwidth usage, data balance, and expiry dates across router hotspots.
- Contributed significantly to the software development of the AMPATH Patient Feedback
  Application, facilitating the gathering of valuable patient feedback and calculation of the Net
  Promoter Score, enhancing healthcare services for over 24 million Kenyans.
- Acquired in-depth understanding of Open Medical Record System (OpenMRS).

#### **HONORS AND AWARD**

**JULY 2023** 

#### **DIT Q1 HEROES - HUSTLER FUND DELIVERY TEAM, SAFARICOM**

Development and successful presidential launch of the Hustler Fund product

**DEC 2023** 

### SAFARICOM GROUP CEO AWARDS, SAFARICOM

Celebrated for championing mission execution, embodied the Spirit of Safaricom, **delivered** initiatives that have positively impacted our Customers, Colleagues, Community and Company

**MARCH 2024** 

#### **VODACOM HACK-A-LYMPICS, VODACOM**

Received a certificate of appreciation for winning Kenya's Innovation Finalist award and representing Kenya in the Africa Innovation Competition as part of the winning team.

### **EDUCATION**

**DEC 2019** 

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, MASENO UNIVERSITY

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certificate in IT Essentials (Cisco Networking Academy)
- Certificate in CCNA Routing and Switching: Routing and Switching Essentials (*Cisco Networking Academy*)
- Certificate in CCNA Routing and Switching: Scaling Networks (Cisco Networking Academy)
- Certificate in CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks (Cisco Networking Academy)
- Agile Foundation (*LinkedIn*)
- Spring: Framework in Depth (*LinkedIn*)
- AWS Essential Training for Developers (*LinkedIn*)

## **AREAS OF INTREST**

- Machine learning
- Cloud computing
- Project Management